Help on module main:

NAME
    main

CLASSES
    builtins.object
        Bus
        Client
    
    class Bus(builtins.object)
     |  A simulation of bus.
     |  
     |  Simulate the basic function and attributes of bus, It can receive and store data and indicate its own voltage level.
     |  
     |  Attributes:
     |      data: A tuple with max length of 5 elements to receive and store data.
     |      voltage_flag: An integer indicates current Bus voltage level.
     |  
     |  Data descriptors defined here:
     |  
     |  __dict__
     |      dictionary for instance variables (if defined)
     |  
     |  __weakref__
     |      list of weak references to the object (if defined)
     |  
     |  ----------------------------------------------------------------------
     |  Data and other attributes defined here:
     |  
     |  data = [None, None, None, None, None]
     |  
     |  voltage_flag = 0
    
    class Client(builtins.object)
     |  Client(name)
     |  
     |  A simulation of client on the ethernet.
     |  
     |  Simulate an ethernet client who is able to report and reset its own status, generate data needed to be sent and send
     |  data under CSMA/CD protocol.
     |  
     |  Attributes:
     |       _max_collision_endure: A constant set to 16 indicates max collision collision_time that can be endured before
     |       dropping the data and report failure.
     |       name: A string object describing the name of the client instance.
     |       data: A string with length of 5 carrying data to be sent.
     |       success_timer: An integer object times the number of successful sending action.
     |       fail_timer: An integer object times the number of failed sending action.
     |       global_timer: An integer object times the number of sending action either succeed or fail.
     |       collision_timer: An integer object set to be same value of _max_collision_endure as default times the number of
     |       collision on a single sending procedure and will be reset to default value after every sending procedure.
     |       send_ok: A integer object set to 0 as default to indicate whether data has all been sent out.
     |  
     |  Methods defined here:
     |  
     |  __init__(self, name)
     |      Init Client class with name.
     |  
     |  collision_handler(self)
     |      Handle collision according to current situation.
     |  
     |  get_backoff_time(self, collision_time)
     |      Generate backoff time.
     |      
     |      Generate backoff time using binary exponential backoff algorithm and collision time given.
     |      
     |      Args:
     |          collision_time: An integer value indicating how many times collisions have happened.
     |      
     |      Returns:
     |          Randomly decide backoff time.
     |  
     |  get_data(self)
     |      Generate new data to send
     |  
     |  report(self)
     |      Report current status.
     |  
     |  reset_all(self)
     |      Generate new data and reset all timer to default.
     |  
     |  reset_collision_timer(self)
     |      Reset collision timer to default.
     |  
     |  send(self)
     |      Kick start sending procedure.
     |  
     |  sender(self)
     |      Send data under CSMA/CD protocol.
     |  
     |  update_timer_on_failure(self)
     |      Update all related timer if sending procedure fail.
     |  
     |  update_timer_on_success(self)
     |      Update all related timer if sending procedure succeed.
     |  
     |  validate_sending(self)
     |      Validate sending data and update related timer and indicator.
     |  
     |  wait_util_free(self)
     |      Monitor Bus until it's free.
     |  
     |  ----------------------------------------------------------------------
     |  Data descriptors defined here:
     |  
     |  __dict__
     |      dictionary for instance variables (if defined)
     |  
     |  __weakref__
     |      list of weak references to the object (if defined)

FUNCTIONS
    clear_log()
    
    report_work()
    
    send_work()
        Send 5 times of data.

DATA
    client_a = <main.Client object>
    client_b = <main.Client object>

FILE
    d:\projects\csma_cd\main.py


